soundcu.com 2004-10-09

# Sound Credit Union

  |  |   
---|---  
 |   
 |   
 |   
 |   
 |   
 |   
 |   
  |    
| 

Protecting your Personal Information

Sound Credit Union Privacy Policy

**Our Privacy Pledge**. At Sound Credit Union we respect the privacy of our members. We recognize the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of your personal financial information. This notice describes the privacy policy and practices followed by Sound Credit Union and our affiliate, Tacoma Credit Union Services, Inc. This notice explains the types of member information we collect and under what circumstances we may share it.

**Member Information We Collect**. We collect only relevant information about members in order to establish and maintain your account and services as the law allows or requires us to collect. We may collect personal and financial information about you which is Nonpublic (member information). The member information we collect varies depending on the accounts and services you request and use. We collect information about you from the following sources:

_Application Information_. We retain personal information we receive from you on any application you provide to us or our affiliate for membership, deposit accounts, EFT services, loans, financial planning, securities brokerage, insurance or other Credit Union services. Application information includes: your name, address, e-mail address, social security number, birth date, phone number, drivers license number, employment, financial status, and credit history.

_Your Transactions_. We retain your transaction information any time you perform a transaction on one of your accounts, including ATM or card transactions, loan advances, transactions through C.U.B.E. Online banking, Online Bill Payer, over the phone or at a branch. Transaction information includes: your account number, the date, the amount, and the location of the transaction. Our affiliate may also provide us with reports on your securities and insurance transactions.

_Credit Reports_. When we evaluate your application for an account or service, we may request a credit report about you from a consumer reporting agency. We retain the personal and credit history information about you and we may use it to evaluate your future account service requests.

_Online_. We obtain information online when you visit our website, _[www.soundcu.com](http://www.soundcu.com/)_. This includes retaining information you provide to us on an online application, through Online Bill Payer, a C.U.B.E. Online Banking transaction, or by e-mail.

**Our Sharing of Member Information**. In order to provide financial services to you, we share certain information about you with our affiliates and third party service providers. However, we limit any information sharing to the extent necessary to service your account or offer new services to you. If we share your information, it is with the goal of bringing you quality services, more choices, and greater convenience. Information we may have about former members is shared or disclosed only if it is required to enforce or administer an account or as required by law.

_Sharing Information with Credit Union Affiliates_. Our wholly-owned affiliate, Tacoma Credit Union Services, Inc. provides financial services, including financial planning, securities and insurance products. Also, our affiliate CU Dealer Direct LLC provides auto-lending services to us. We may share personal information (name, address, account number, and phone number) and account information (type of accounts, account balances, and transaction history) with our affiliates so they can serve you more efficiently. Our affiliates maintain the same privacy standards as the Credit Union.

_Sharing Information with Third Party Service Providers_. In order for us to conduct our operations, including servicing your account and processing your transactions, we need to share information with our service providers, including: data processing companies, check, ATM and other payment processing companies, payment networks, loan service providers, insurance companies, collection agencies, credit reporting agencies, securities brokerage and financial planners and service providers with whom we have marketing agreements. These service providers act on our behalf and have agreed in writing to keep the member information we provide to them confidential. We share the following categories of information to third party service providers depending on the specific services provided:

\- Personal information (name, address, account number, and phone number)

\- Account information (type of accounts, account balances, transaction history)

\- Transaction information (dates, amounts, locations and type of transaction)

We do not sell member information nor share your account numbers with independent third party marketers offering their products and services. While we may assist in offering the financial products and services of our affiliates or third party service providers, we control the member information used to make such offers.

_Sharing Information as Legally Required or Permitted_. We may share any member information of yours in response to a lawful request issued by a court, government agency, or regulatory authority or as permitted by law in order to administer or enforce your account. We may also share our experience information about you with credit bureaus. Our reporting to credit bureaus is governed by the Fair Credit Reporting Act, which affords you the right to make sure that your credit bureau reports are accurate.

**Our Confidentiality and Security Safeguards**. We maintain strict policies and security controls to assure that member information in our computer systems and files is protected. Our employees are permitted access to member information that they may need to perform their jobs, to provide service to you, and as necessary to conduct a transaction or respond to your inquiries. All employees are trained to respect member privacy. No one except our employees has access to the Credit Union computer system and records storage. The Credit Union has established internal security controls, including physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the information you provide us and the information we collect about you. We will continue to review our internal security controls to safeguard your member information as we employ new technology in the future.

**Online Privacy Protections**. At our website, _[www.soundcu.com](http://www.soundcu.com/)_ , you may apply for accounts and services and you may communicate with us via e-mail. To protect the information you provide us online, we use multiple levels of security. The application information we accept online, our C.U.B.E. Online banking service, and our Online Bill Payer service relies on industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption to secure your transaction information and communication. Generally, our e-mails are not secure. However, if we ask you to e-mail us information other than your name, address, e-mail address, and phone number, it will be obtained using a secure (SSL encryption) e-mail form.

When you visit our web site, you can access site information, without revealing your personal identity. However, in order to help us identify you for future site visits, we use cookies to track your visit. A cookie is a piece of information that our web server stores on your computer hard drive and retrieves later. The cookie will not request, require, or collect personal identity information and you remain anonymous. Your member information is not accessed by or stored within a cookie in any way.

**Protecting Children’s Information Privacy**. Our online financial services are not designed for or directed toward children. We do not knowingly solicit or collect data from children and we do not knowingly market to children online. We recognize that protecting children’s identities and online privacy is important and that responsibility rests with us and with parents.

**Privacy Policy Inquiries**. If you have any questions about our privacy practices, contact us by calling (253) 383-2016 or (800) 562-8130, sending us an e-mail at [info@soundcu.com](mailto:info@soundcu.com), or writing to us at: Sound Credit Union, ATTN: Privacy Policy Inquiries, P.O. Box 1595, Tacoma, WA 98401.

We reserve the right to amend our Privacy Policy at anytime and we will notify you as required by law.

For questions about your account, please email [Member Service](mailto:info@soundcu.com).  
Questions or Feedback about our site? Please email  the [Webmaster](mailto:webmaster@soundcu.com).  
Copyright ©2004 Sound Credit Union.  All rights reserved.  Privacy Notice
